sportlive.co.za 2011-12-01

# Privacy and Policy - Sport LIVE

Please read the [Privacy Policy](http://www.sportlive.co.za/?filter=privacyAndPolicy) and our notices regarding [Terms of Use](http://www.sportlive.co.za/?filter=termsandconditions) and Forums. By continuing to use the Sport LIVE, you agree to abide by the terms of these documents. 

1\. Introduction

1.1 This privacy policy ("this Privacy Policy") must be read together with the Terms and Condition. Unless defined elsewhere, terms in this Privacy Policy shall bear the meaning ascribed to them in the Terms and Conditions.

1.2 The Owner is committed to bringing You information tailored to Your individual needs and recognises the importance of protecting the privacy of personally identifiable information collected about our users.

1.3 In adopting this Privacy Policy, the Owner wishes to balance its legitimate business interests when collecting and using your personal information and Your reasonable expectation of privacy. In this respect, the Owner will take reasonable steps to prevent unauthorised access to, or disclosure of your personal information. However, the Owner does not guarantee that Your personal information shall be 100% secure.

1.4 By continuing to use this Web Site, You agree to the terms and conditions of this Privacy Policy. If You do not agree with this Privacy Policy, please do not continue to Use The Web Site.

1.5 You agree that the Owner may collect, collate, process and/or store Your personal information (as this phrase is defined in the ECT Act) ("Collect") for, amongst other things, the purposes of (i) providing You with access to the Web Site and the Web Site Content, (ii) bringing You information tailored to Your needs, and (iii) conducting research.

1.6 The Owner reserves the right to vary the terms of this Privacy policy, which will be made available on the Web Site. It is your responsibility to familiarise Yourself with the most recent version of this Privacy Policy.

2\. What personal information is Collected?

The Owner may Collect personal information that may include (with limitation), Your name and e-mail address, information relating to Your race, gender, ethnic or social origin, age, well-being, disability, personal opinions, views or preferences.

3\. When is Your personal information Collected?

3.1 Personal information may be Collected in several ways.

3.2 Some personal information may be Collected when You register for services on the Web Site, during the carrying out of demographic research, or when promotions, competitions or surveys are held.

3.3 You acknowledge that promotions and competitions on the Web Site may be sponsored by third parties, or may be co-sponsored by the Owner together with third parties. You agree that some or all Your personal information may be shared with such third party.

3.4 You also acknowledge that advertisers or other web sites that have links on the Web Site may also Collect Your personal information. You agree that the information processing practices of those advertisers and other web sites are neither under the control of the Owner nor regulated by this Privacy Policy.

4\. How Your personal information is used?

4.1 The primary goal in Collecting Your personal information is to provide You with a better online experience, which may include, interactive communications, online shopping and other services.

4.2 Your personal information may be used to:

4.2.1 deliver to You more relevant and targeted content and advertisements, such as banner advertisements;

4.2.2 conduct research related to demographics, interests and on line habits;

4.2.3 compile profiles for statistical purposes. You agree that the Owner may trade with those profiles and statistical data. While the Owner will attempt to ensure that the profiles or statistical data cannot be linked to You, the Owner does not guarantee that third parties may not be able to link such profiles and statistical data to You. You hereby indemnify the Owner against any loss, liability, expense, claim, penalty or damage suffered by You, whether direct, indirect, special or consequential, arising from or in relation to any third party being able to link such profiles and statistical data to You;

5\. With whom is Your information shared?

5.1 While the Owner will attempt not to disclose any of Your personal information to third parties, except when we have your permission or in the legitimate business interests of the Owner, the Owner does not guarantee that Your personal information will not be shared with third parties without Your permission.

5.2 Your personal information may also be shared under the following circumstances:

5.2.1 where the law requires that the Owner disclose Your personal information;

5.2.2 to monitor web traffic: web servers serving the Web Site automatically collect information about pages You visit. This information is used for internal review, to tailor information to individual visitors and for traffic audits. This information (as well as information from third-party market researchers), on an aggregated, anonymous basis, is provided to advertisers advertising on the Web Site. Should You provide personal information online as part of an online advertising promotion or in order to access a third party service, such information may be provided directly to the advertiser or the third party concerned;

5.2.3 Promotions: many promotions offer opportunities to request additional information from sponsors or third parties. When You request more information about a particular promotion, Your e-mail address may be shared with the sponsor of that promotion;

5.2.4 Online shopping: if You make a purchase from an online store or merchant, the information obtained during Your visit to those stores (including tracking information, cookies, credit card number and contact information) is provided to the merchants. This is to enable transactions to take place;

5.2.5 Third parties: online merchants providing services in association with the Owner have separate privacy and data collection practices. You agree that the Owner has no responsibility or liability for third party policies. For more information regarding the merchant, their store, and their privacy policies, return to that store?s home page and click on the appropriate link;

5.2.6 Editorial purposes: Your personal information may be used by the Owner for editorial purposes. For example, this may include information You provide during an online survey conducted by our editors.

5.2.7 Legal: the Owner may also disclose Your personal information in special cases, where the Owner has reason to believe that such disclosure is necessary to identify, contact or bring legal action against a party who may be breaching the Terms and Conditions or may be causing injury to or interference with (either intentionally or unintentionally) the Owner?s rights or property, other users, or anyone else that could be harmed by such activities; and

5.2.8 For statistics and advertisement purposes: the Owner may perform statistical analyses in order to measure interest in the various areas of the Web Site (for product development purposes) and to inform advertisers as to how many consumers have seen or "clicked" on their advertising banners. The Owner also uses demographic information to allow advertising banners on the Web Site to be targeted, in aggregate.

5.3 What are cookies and how are they used?

5.4 Cookies are pieces of information a Web Site transfers to a user?s hard drive for record-keeping purposes. Cookies make surfing the web easier for You by saving Your preferences and, tracking Your online habits, traffic patterns, and making sure You do not see the same advertisement too often. The use of cookies is an industry standard.

5.5 The Owner may place a "cookie" on Your browser to store and sometimes track information about You.

5.6 While most browsers are initially set up to accept cookies, You can reset Your browser to refuse all cookies or indicate when a cookie is being sent. Please, note that some parts of the Web Site will not function properly if You refuse cookies. For example, without cookies, You will not be able to set personalized TV Guide preferences. You may occasionally get cookies from third party advertisers. The Owner does not control these cookies. The use of advertising cookies sent by third-party advertisers is an industry standard.

6\. Use of IP Address

An IP address is a number that is automatically assigned to a computer whenever it is connected to the Internet. The Owner also logs IP addresses, or the location of computers on the Internet. The Owner collects IP addresses for the purposes of system administration, to report aggregate information to our advertisers, and to audit the use of the Web Site. The Owner does not ordinarily link IP addresses to personal information, which means that Your session may remain anonymous. However, the Owner cannot guarantee that this will always be the case. For example, it may be necessary to identify a particular user when it is necessary to enforce compliance with the Terms and Conditions or to protect our service Web Site, customers or other interests.

7\. Links to other sites

When You are on the Web Site, You could be directed to other sites that are beyond the Owner?s control. These other web sites may send their own cookies to You, collect data or solicit personal information. The Owner does not control the privacy policies of any advertisers, sponsors or other third party web sites.

8\. Security

The importance of security for all personal information associated with You is of the utmost concern to us. While the Owner exercises great care in providing secure transmission of Your personal information, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. The Owner cannot guarantee the security of any information you transmit to, or from the Owner?s Web Site.

9\. E-Mail

The Owner may periodically send e-mails to You about services, products or promotions offered by the Owner and its advertisers to the e-mail address provided by You.

10\. Policies for Individuals Under 13 years of Age

Sport LIVE encourages parents, teachers and guardians to spend time online with their children and to participate in the activities offered on the Web Site. No information (including personal information) should be submitted to or posted on the Web Site by any person under 13 years of age without the consent of their parent, teacher or guardian.
